Guide to the Student Action With Farmworkers Records, 1950-2013 and undated, bulk 1992-2010
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Student Projects Series, 1986-2011, and undated, (46 boxes)
  - Audio/Visual and Digital Material Subseries, 1990-2004, and undated, (6 boxes)
    - 2002 ITF guided reports (Box 69)
    - ITF documentary projects 2005, (3 folders) (Box 69)
    - ITF 2006 documentary intern Bart Evans (Box 69)
    - ITF SAF/CDs Our Stories/Our Dreams Documentary Project, (1 folders) (Box 69)
    - ITF Documentary Project 2006-2007, (7 folders) (Box 69)
    - ITF Folklife Documentary Project, (1 of 2) (Box 69)
    - ITF Folklife Documentary Project, (2 of 2) (Box 70)
    - ITF Misc. Media (Box 70)
    - ITF W-3 Work with 3 Students (Box 70)
    - ITF 2008 Folklife Documentary Project (Box 70)
    - ITF 2008 Documentary Project, (7 folders) (Box 70)
    - AIM 2001 NC Farmworker Class, Justin Fishkin (Box 70)
    - AIM 2001 NC Farmworker Class, Beth O'Donnell (Box 70)
    - AIM 2001 NC Farmworker Class, Alison Blaine (Box 70)
    - Levante rough cut and back-up file cds and dvds (Box 70)
- Printed Material Series, 1978-2009, and undated, (9 boxes)
  Contains SAF's publications, SAF press coverage, and farmworker related print material.
  - Binder Subseries, 1988-2009, and undated, (3 boxes)
    Contains printed material collected in binders produced by SAF and others. Contains information on various issues of import to migrant farmworker communities and community education material, such as health and legal resources.
    - Migrant and Seasonal Farmworkers in NC, 1988, (2 folders) (Box 71)
    - Misc. Farm Stuff, 1992 (Box 71)
    - Presentation Info, 1994 (Box 71)
    - Stop! Child Labor, 1996 (Box 71)
    - Camp Health Aide Manual, 1997, (4 folders) (Box 71)
    - NC: Farmworkers Services Coordinating Committee, 1997, (3 folders) (Box 71)
    - SC Migrant Health Program: 1998 Outreach Worker Orientation, (2 folders) (Box 71)
    - Legal Immigration Forum, 2001 March, (2 folders) (Box 71)
    - 2001-2004, (1-2 of 12 folders) (Box 71)
    - 2001-2004, (3-12 of 12 folders) (Box 72)
    - 2005 Publication, (6 folders) (Box 72)
    - 2006 Publication, (5 folders) (Box 72)
    - 2007 Publication, (3 folders) (Box 73)
    - 2008 Publication, (4 folders) (Box 73)
    - 2009 Publication, (3 folders) (Box 73)
    - Compilation of Health Materials, undated, (6 folders) (Box 73)
    - Newcomer Arts: A Strategy for Successful Integration, undated, (2 folders) (Box 73)
  - Theses Subseries, 1991-2004, (1 box)
    Contains masters theses related to farmworkers and migrant workers, many specifically focusing on North Carolina. Topics include workers rights, education, identity, and women.
    - Corrie, Carolyn. 'And Justice for All?' The Migrant Farmworker Crisis and the Failure of Liberal Reform, 1991. (Box 74)
    - Callahan, Cathy. Stranded, Uprooted and Voiceless: Latin American Farmworking Women in NC, 1992. (Box 74)
    - Mosher, Kathleen C. Delicate Art, Low Pay: The Legacy of Crab Pickers in NC, 1993. (Box 74)
    - Hickle, Andrea. Focus Groups, Interviews, and Lay Health Advisor training with Mexican Migrant Farmworkers, 1996. (Box 74)
    - Ludwig, Erik K. First Class Education and 'Second Hand' Workers, 1998 April. (Box 74)
    - Bagby, Joe. Sweat Inequality: The Social Alienation of Mexican Migrant Farmworkers in NC, 2000. (Box 74)
    - Payne, Brian. Taking Back the Reins of Identity Transformation, 2000. (Box 74)
    - Rhodes, Catherine R. Modern-Day Slavery: the Involuntary Servitude of NC's H-2A Farmworkers Today, 2000. (Box 74)
    - Abernathy, Lee E. Education of a Gringa: Encounters with Mexicans in the US, 2001. (Box 74)
    - Sugg, Jennifer H. ESL and the Education of Latino Students in Lee County of NC, 2001. (Box 74)
    - Etienne, Stephanie. Provider Knowledge of Farmworker Agricultural Chemical Exposure, 2004. (Box 74)
    - Student papers, (6 folders) (Box 75)
    - Wilson, Julie. Diversity in Solidarity: Student Action with Farmworkers' Archive of Intern Writing, 2007. (Box 94)
  - Publications Subseries, 1978-2008, and undated, (4 boxes)
    Contains publications such as serials, newspapers, pamphlets, booklets, reports, etc. related to migrant workers, farmworkers, and SAF. Many are activist and community based publications and focus on North Carolina.
    - Judson, Horace. Reflections of a Former Migrant, 1978. (Box 76)
    - Harvesting the Harvesters, circa 1985, (10 volumes in 2 folders) (Box 76)
    - Maps of Farmworker Camps in NC, 1988 Summer. (Box 76)
    - Baca, Jimmy Santiago. Immigrants in Our own Land and Selected Early Poems, 1990. (Box 76)
    - Duke: A Magazine for Alumni and Friends, 1991 June-July. (Box 76)
    - Into the Fields: A Guide and Resource Manual for Student Initiatives with Farmworkers, 1991., (2 folders, 2 copies) (Box 76)
    - Life's Learning: Education with Three Mexican Families in NC, 1991. (Box 76)
    - NC Farm Labor Rules and Regulations, 1991. (Box 76)
    - Campus Outreach, 1993 Jan./Feb., (2 copies) (Box 76)
    - From the Ground Up, 1993 July-1998 Fall. (Box 76)
    - From the Ground Up, 1999 Spring-2002 Summer. (Box 76)
    - From the Ground Up, 2002 Fall/Winter-2006 Winter. (Box 76)
    - From the Ground Up, 2006 Fall/Winter-2008 Winter. (Box 76)
    - Tobacco Road, 1995 April., (2 copies) (Box 76)
    - Into the Fields: A Report on Migrant and Seasonal Farmworkers in MN, 1995 Oct. (Box 76)
    - NCSU, 1995 Fall (Box 76)
      Alumni Magazine.
    - L&S Link, 1995 Nov. (Box 76)
    - North Carolina Humanities, 1995. (Box 76)
    - Community Change, 1996 Spring. (Box 76)
    - Fields without Borders, 1996., (2 copies) (Box 76)
    - Johnson, Chris. Photocards, 1996. (Box 76)
    - La Voz de Carolina, 1996 June 30. (Box 76)
    - La Voz de Carolina, 1996 July 31. (Box 76)
    - The Prism, 1996 Nov. (Box 77)
    - Student Intern Perspectives, 1996. (Box 77)
    - The Cost of Your Shirt, 1997 (Box 77)
    - Into the Fields, Mobilizing Students to Work with Farmworkers on Campuses and in Communities, 1997., (2 copies) (Box 77)
    - Testimonies from the Fields, 1997. (Box 77)
    - Living the American Dream, 1998. (Box 77)
      Print-out version.
    - Living the American Dream: Economic Justice for Farmworkers, 1998., (2 copies) (Box 77)
      Bound version.
    - NC Crossroads, 1998 Sep./Oct. (Box 77)
    - A Profile of Demographic, Occupational, and Health-Related Characteristics of The Migrant and Settled (Seasonal) Hired Farmworker Population of FL, 1998. (Box 77)
    - SAF/NCSU Migrant Scholarship, 1998. (Box 77)
    - Volunteer 101, 1998 Fall., (2 copies) (Box 77)
    - Various event invitations and postcard flyers, 1998-2003 and undated. (Box 77)
    - Farmworker Folklife, 1999. (Box 77)
    - Juntos con Nuestra Herencia, 1999. (Box 77)
    - Life as we See It, 1999. (Box 77)
    - Photo Blitz, 1999. (Box 77)
      Poster.
    - Report on Latino Culture and Traditional Arts in TN, 1999 Nov. (Box 77)
    - Uprooting Injustice, 1999., (2 folders, 2 copies) (Box 77)
    - College Choices Guide for Migrant Students and Parents, 2000. (Box 77)
    - Communities Against Sweatshops, 2000. (Box 77)
    - False Profits: Who Wins, Who Loses when the IMF, World Banks, and WTO Come to Town, 2000. (Box 77)
    - Globalization in our Front Yard, 2000. (Box 77)
    - How to Start an AIM, 2000. (Box 77)
    - Predictors of Incidence and Prevalence of Green Tobacco Sickness among Latino Farmworkers in NC, 2000-2001 (Box 77)
    - Recollections of Home, 2000., (2 copies) (Box 77)
    - The Voice of Farmworkers, 2000. (Box 77)
    - Word Wide: Writers of the Americas, 2000. (Box 77)
    - Action, Inspiration, Motivation: Randolph County AIM Club Members Share their Experiences, 2001 Spring. (Box 78)
    - College Choices Guide for Migrant Students and Parents, 2001. (Box 78)
    - Cultured Ground: A Compilation of Folklife Documentaries, 2001. (Box 78)
    - Hemming, Jill. Neighborhood Voices, 2001. (Box 78)
    - Learning About Green Tobacco Sickness, 2001. (Box 78)
    - Media Guide to Covering Farmworkers in NC, 2001. (Box 78)
    - Soul Talk: Luis Rodriguez in North Carolina, 2001., (3 copies) (Box 78)
    - To Be Rather than to Seem: Reflections on Race in NC, 2001. (Box 78)
    - Urban Latino, 2001 Apr./May., (2 copies) (Box 78)
    - From Orchards to the Internet: Confronting Contingent Work Abuse, 2002. (Box 78)
    - North Carolina Humanities, 2002 Spring. (Box 78)
    - SAF: Solidarity Since 1992, 2002. (Box 78)
    - Divinity: Duke University, 2003 Winter., (2 copies) (Box 78)
    - Doña Genoveva Manos que Brindan Salud, 2003. (Box 78)
    - NC Crossroads, 2003 May., (2 folders, 2 copies) (Box 78)
    - Tallando Tradiciones, 2003. (Box 78)
    - Community News, 2004 Spring. (Box 78)
    - Conflict Management, 2004. (Box 78)
    - From Cambodia to Greensboro, 2004. (Box 78)
    - Blessing the Hands, 2005. (Box 78)
    - Farmworker Justice Fund, 2005. (Box 78)
    - The Guestworker, 2005. (Box 78)
    - The Other Immigrants, 2005. (Box 78)
    - Increasing Access to Food and Nutrition for Migrant Children, 2006. (Box 78)
    - Memories of Carolinian Immigrants, 2006. (Box 78)
    - Not Yo Mama's Home Cookin': The Changing Face of Rural NC, 2006. (Box 78)
    - Phelps, Ellen. NC Migrant Housing and Safety Standards, 2006. (Box 78)
    - 15 Year Anniversary, 2007. (Box 78)
      Event pamphlet.
    - Children in the Fields, 2007. (Box 78)
    - Close to Slavery, circa 2007. (Box 78)
    - Secret, Mosi Farm Team, Independent, 2007 Aug. 15. (Box 78)
    - Crossroads, Fall 2007. (Box 78)
    - Gracias por los Campesinos, 2008. (Box 78)
      Calendar.
    - The Catalyst, undated. (Box 78)
    - College Choice Guide for Migrant Students and Parents, undated., (2 folders, 2 copies) (Box 78)
    - FLOC...In the Community, undated. (Box 78)
    - Guestworkers and Enganchadores, undated. (Box 78)
      Powerpoint printout.
    - The Human Cost of Food, undated., (2 copies) (Box 78)
      Book cover.
    - Mexico Infopak, undated. (Box 79)
    - Not From Here/Not From There, undated. (Box 79)
      postcard flyer.
    - A Resource Guide to Scholarships for Hispanic and Migrant Students, undated. (Box 79)
    - SAF Dismantling Oppression Philosophy and Roles, undated. (Box 79)
    - SAF Impact! undated. (Box 79)
    - SAF Intern Referral Service Directory, undated. (Box 79)
    - SAF Resources Offered, undated. (Box 79)
    - Various publications and writings of Hector Neri, undated. (Box 79)
      Also includes correspondence about the writings included.
    - Food and Justice, United Farmworkers, 1985-1988 (Box 94)
    - Struggle for Justice, A Tribute to Cesar Chavez, 1993 (Box 94)
    - NC Crossroads, 1998 Sep. (Box 94)
    - Directory, National Farmworker Ministry, 1998 (Box 94)
    - Cuban/Haitian Entrant Program, Interpreter/Translator Directory (Box 94)
    - Leo Cuellar Says: Work Smart... Work Safely... With Farm Chemicals (Box 94)
  - Children's Books Subseries, 1993-1997, (1 box) (Box 79)
    Contains children's books about migrant farmworkers.
    - Alman, Linda Jacobs and Enrique O. Sanchez. Amelia's Road, 1993. (Box 79)
    - Dorros, Arthur. Radio Man, 1993. (Box 79)
    - Herrera, Juan Felipe. Calling the Doves, 1995. (Box 79)
    - Ada, Alma Flor. Gathering the Sun, 1997. (Box 79)
- Joan Preiss Series, 1950-2005, and undated, (5 boxes)
  Joan Papert Preiss was a frequent collaborator of SAF. She was a community and labor movement organizer in Durham, N.C.; chair of the Triangle Friends of the United Farm Workers; board member of the National Farm Worker Ministry; member of the Farmworker Ministry Commission, N.C. Council of Churches. This series contains a variety of printed materials, primarily articles and newsletters, as well as correspondence, protest ephemera, promotional material for unions and activist organizations, meeting notes, etc. Undated materials are organized by subject. The series also contains student papers and photographs. The materials relate to migrants and farmworkers both in North Carolina and throughout the United States. Folders are organized chronologically.
  Along with the standard restrictions of this collection, Boxes 3 and 4 are RESTRICTED due to the inclusion of student papers. Please contact the Rubenstein Library for permission to use this box.
  - 1950-1984 (Box 80)
  - 1985-1999 (Box 81)
  - 2000-2007 (Box 82)
  - Student papers, 1979-2000 (Box 82)
  - Student papers, 1979-2000 (Box 83)
  - Articles and newsletters, undated (Box 83)
  - Correspondence, undated (Box 83)
  - Ephemera and promotional material, undated (Box 83)
  - Notes, undated (Box 83)
  - Pamphlets and booklets, undated (Box 83)
  - Write-in forms, petitions, and donation forms, undated (Box 83)
  - Photographs, 1984-1999 and undated (Box 83)
  - Oversized materials, 2004 and 2005, (2 items) (Box 84)
- Oversize Material and Ephemera Series, 1992-2010, and undated, (9 boxes)
  Contains oversize materials related to SAF's organized protests and boycotts and Levante activist theater group. Includes material from Burger King, Subway, Tomatoes, and Mt. Olive boycotts and protests. Also contains SAF publicity ephemera.
  - Taco Bell (Oversize-box 85)
    Protest materials related to the tomato industry.
  - Burger King (Oversize-box 85)
  - Subway (Oversize-box 85)
  - AG Mart (Oversize-box 85)
  - Tomatoes, general (Oversize-box 85)
  - Protesting Folgers and promoting Fair Trade coffee at Duke (Oversize-box 86)
  - Mt. Olive (Oversize-box 86)
  - Gallos (Oversize-box 86)
  - Outreach and meeting information (Oversize-box 87)
    Includes material featuring schedules, club members, activity reports, plays, etc.
  - General protest materials (Oversize-box 87)
    These materials do not identify a specific company or industry.
  - B&B Products and Sun Beauty Yams (Oversize-box 88)
  - Outreach and meeting information (Oversize-box 88)
  - Prime Mushrooms (Oversize-box 89)
  - Campbell's (Oversize-box 89)
  - Subway tomatoes (Oversize-box 89)
  - General protest materials, outreach and meeting information (Oversize-box 89)
  - Public relations and outreach (Box 90)
    Newspaper articles, publications, etc.
  - AFL-CIO boycott ephemera (Box 90)
  - Taco Bell (Box 90)
  - Subway (Box 90)
  - T-shirts (Box 91)
  - Write in campaign postcards (Box 91)
  - Stickers (Box 91)
  - Mug (Box 91)
  - Tshirts (Box 92)
  - AFL-CIO flags/banners (Box 92)
  - "Uvas No" pins (Box 92)
  - "Fast for Life" medal (Box 92)
  - Ni de Aquí/Ni de Allá, Not from Here/Not from There book (Box 93)
  - Recollections of Home poster (Box 93)
  - Mask (Box 93)
  - Artwork (Box 93)
  - Plastic banner (Box 93)
  - Samantha - American Rights at Work award ceremony materials (Box 94)
  - Pesticide Test Kit, from AFL-CIO (Box 94)
- Accession 2013-0079 Series, 1987-2013, (13 boxes)
  Contains administrative files regarding the operation of SAF, including material on workstudy and internships, and its collaborations with other programs and organizations. This series also contains descriptions, narratives, field notes, audiovisual materials and digital records of student documentary projects on farmworkers and social justice. Print publications include newsletters, journals, newspapers and magazines regarding immigrant rights, migrant labor, child labor and workers' health, and audiovisual and digital records include educational and promotional videos regarding the same.
  - Administrative Files Subseries, 2007-2013
    Contains various documents regarding SAF's partnerships with other programs, including Duke Engage, its operating procedures, its workstudy students and interns and various campaigns related to farmworkers and social justice.
    - Bandana Project, 2009 (Box 95)
    - Cesar Chavez Day, 2012 (Box 95)
    - Database 2008-2009 (Box 95)
    - Databse 2009-2010 (Box 95)
    - Database 2010-2011 (Box 95)
    - Duke Engage, 2010 (Box 95)
    - Duke Engage, 2010-2011 (Box 95)
    - Farmworker Awareness Campaign, 2009 (Box 95)
    - Farmworker Awareness Campaign, 2010 (Box 95)
    - Farmworker Awareness Campaign, 2011 (Box 95)
    - Farmworker Awareness Week, 2011 (Box 95)
    - Farmworker Institute, 2008-2010 (Box 95)
    - Images for fliers, undated (Box 95)
    - Into the Fields administrative files, 2010-2011, (1 of 7) (Box 95)
    - Into the Fields administrative files, 2010-2011, (2-7 of 7) (Box 96)
    - Into the Fields student files, 2007-2013, (14 of 30) (Box 96)
    - Into the Fields student files, 2007-2013, (15-30 of 30 folders) (Box 97)
    - Into the Fields and Sowing Seeds for Change programs administrative files, 2011, (9 folders) (Box 97)
    - Levante, 2010-2011 (Box 97)
    - Levante Leadership Institute and SOS orientation, 2010-2011 (Box 97)
    - Melinda and Laxmi anniversary parties, 2011 (Box 97)
    - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 98)
    - Operating procedures and personal policies, 2008 Nov.-2009 Nov. (Box 98)
    - Original drawings, undated (Box 98)
    - Preiss, Joan Papert memorial service, 2012 (Box 98)
    - RBMSCL/UA exhibit separation sheets, 2012 (Box 98)
    - Sowing Seeds for Change decline, 2011 (Box 98)
    - Stenciles and artwork, undated (Box 98)
    - Student Action with Farmworkers staff FAC, 2011 (Box 98)
    - SOS administrative files, 2010-2011, (9 folders) (Box 98)
    - Workstudy, 2009-2010 (Box 98)
    - Workstudy, 2010-2011 (Box 98)
  - Documentary Projects Subseries, 2008-2011
    Contains descriptions, release forms, photos and negatives, field notes and sketches, and narratives for various documentary projects focusing on farmworkers and social change. Also includes information on financial support offered to SAF alum. All CDs and minidisks migrated to Box 105.
    - Documentary, 2009, (2 folders) (Box 99)
    - Documentary, 2010 (Box 99)
    - Documentary, 2011 (Box 99)
    - Documentary Award, 2008-2009 (Box 99)
    - Documentary Award, 2010 (Box 99)
    - Documentary by Dayanna Diaz, Jennifer Gonzalez and April Simon, 2009 (Box 99)
      CD-R migrated to Box 105.
    - Documentary by Maria Mondujano and Jazmin Posas, 2009 (Box 99)
    - Documentary work, 2009, (2 folders) (Box 100)
      Discs migrated to Box 105.
  - Print Publications Subseries, 1988-2012 and undated
    Contains journals, reports, newsletters and other miscellaneous publications of various organizations concerned with labor rights, immigrant rights, worker health, philanthropy, poverty, and child labor. Includes SAF publications from 1990-2000.
    - Action, Inspiration, Motivation: Randolph County AIM Club Members Share Their Experiences, Spring, 2001 (Box 101)
    - Articles, 1988-2000, (2 folders) (Box 101)
    - Association of Farmworker Opportunity Programs, "America's Farmworker Children: Harvest of Broken Dreams," 2011 (Box 101)
    - Bachpan Bachao Andolan promotional material, undated (Box 101)
    - Common Ground: A publication for the N.C. Center for Nonprofits newsletters, Summer and Fall, 2012 (Box 101)
    - Duke Magazine, 2012 Jul.-Aug. (Box 101)
    - From the Ground Up: A Publication of Student Action with Farmworkers newsletters, Fall/Winter, 1999 (Box 101)
    - Georgetown Journal on Poverty and Law Policy, The Environment and Social Injustice of Farmworker Pesticide Exposure, Spring, 2012 (Box 101)
    - Grassroots Fundraising Journal, Volume 30, Number 6, 2011 Nov.-Dec. (Box 101)
    - Health Outreach Partners, collection of outreach strategies from the field, undated (Box 101)
    - Hispanic National Bar Association, The Promise of the Law, undated (Box 101)
    - Inside Agromedicine newsletters, Summer 2011-Winter/Spring 2013 (Box 101)
    - Independent Weekly, 1999 Feb. and 2007 Aug. (Box 101)
    - International Labor Office/Organization publications, 2005-2011 (Box 101)
    - Latino Studies, Latino/as in the Media, Vol. 9, Number 2-3, Summer/Autumn, 2011 (Box 101)
      Special issue.
    - La Voz Independiente, 2011 Feb. 3 (Box 101)
    - Miscellaneous newsletters, 2011-2012 (Box 101)
    - Miscellaneous print publications, 1993-2012 and undated (Box 102)
    - National Committee for Responsive Philanthropy, Strengthening Democracy, Increasing Opportunities: Impacts of Advocacy, Organizing, and Civic Engagement in the Gulf/Midsouth Region, undated (Box 102)
    - National Committee for Responsive Philanthropy quarterly journal, Spring 2011-Winter 2012/2013 (Box 102)
    - National Farmworker Ministry News and Views, Spring 2011-Fall 2012 (Box 102)
    - National Network for Immigrant and Refugee Rights, Injustice for All: The Rise of the U.S.-Immigration Policing Regime, 2010 Dec. (Box 102)
    - Network News, Catholic Migrant Farmworker Network newsletters, Volume 22, Numbers 1 and 2, Autumn-Winter, 2012 (Box 102)
    - New Solutions: A Journal of Environmental and Occupational Health Policy, Volume 22, Number 2, 2012 (Box 102)
    - North Carolina Justice Center, 2011 (Box 102)
    - North Carolina Medical Journal, Volume 72, Number 6, 2011 Nov.-Dec. (Box 102)
    - Office of Research Integrity newsletter, 2011 Mar. and Sep. (Box 102)
    - Organización Internacional del Trabajo publications, 2012 and undated (Box 102)
    - Piñata Books for Children, Spring, 2011 and 2012 (Box 102)
    - Poverty and Race Research Action Council newsletters, 2011 May/June-2013 Jan./Feb. (Box 102)
    - Pushing Back: Women Workers Speak Out on Free Trad e, Women United for Worker Justice (STITCH), 2004, Aug. (Box 102)
    - Salud! Health and Safety Programs, 2012 Jan.-Nov. (Box 102)
    - Student Action with Farmworkers publication, 1990-1995 (Box 102)
    - Student Action with Farmworkers publication, 1996-2000 (2 folders) (Box 103)
    - Siembra: A Newsletter for Farmworker Friends and Advocates, Fall 2011-Winter 2012 (Box 103)
    - UMOS annual report, 2010-2011 (Box 103)
    - Youth Villages magazine, Spring, 2012 (Box 103)
  - Audiovisual Subseries, 1987-2003 and undated
    Contains videos focusing on migrant workers and migrant labor.
    - 1. Plantation Legislature; 2. Migrant Lay Health Advisors: A Strategy, 16:15, VHS, 1987 (Box 104)
    - Catholic Communications Network, Season of the Migrants, 19:20, VHS, undated (Box 104)
    - Milagritos... Little Miracles: When Communities Create Farmworker Housing, 16:00, VHS, 1998 (Box 104)
    - Justice on the Table: Resources and Discussion Guides for Schools and Religious Audiences, 25:00, VHS, 2003 (Box 104)
  - Digital Records Subseries, 1993-2011 and undated
    Contains various digital records of administrative files and student documentary projects. Some material has been migrated from the Documentary Projects subseries.
    - 35 diskettes, 25 minidisks, 17 CD-Rs, 1993-2011 (Box 105)
  - Ephemera Subseries, 2007 and undated
    Contains miscellaneous ephemera related to immigrant rights, migrant labor and related events.
    - "Migrant farmworkers earn our support" bumper sticker, undated (Box 106)
    - Quinceañera celebration photograph, 2007 Aug. 10 (Box 106)
    - Immigrant rights are civil rights sign, undated (Box 106)
    - Association of Migrant Students t-shirt, undated (Box 106)
    - Puppet, 2003-2004 (Box 107)
      Big Papa is a puppet that was used by SAF's theater group from 2003-2004 to represent the negative aspects of corporate agriculture. The puppet was created by NC sculpture artist Daniel L. Mathewson (1964-2011) for the play Gigantes en los Campos/Giants in the Fields written by NC writer Cara Page. The Big Papa character had few lines, but loomed ominously over scenes in the play as a method of intimidation and mockery of the farmworker characters. The play critiqued the H2A Guestworker Program which brings thousands of farmworkers to labor in the fields of North Carolina picking tobacco, cucumbers and other crops.